Shashi... 茶!
Shashi... tea!
Sapna!
5apna!
把手机给我
Give me my phone
不...
No...
不什么不...先吃你的早点...
What no...have your breakfast first...
你怎么又做成白面包了？
Why don't you stop this white bread...
就不能做成黑面包吗？
why can't you get brown!
那给我吃好了...
Give it to me...
我倒是喜欢白的蓝的红的...什么颜色的都行
I like white blue red...anything
这不行，奶奶...
No Maaji...
你的粥好了
your porridge is ready
我能不能就吃一片薄饼?
Can I eat one parantha at least?
妈妈...你这辈子吃得够多了
Mom...you've had enough paranthas all your life...
现在该喝点粥了
it's time you had porridge now
Shashi，我的饼呢？快点好吗？
Shashi where's my parantha? Hurry up please...
Sagar...你的可可麦精
Sagar...your bournvita
这也是白色的...我要咖啡色的！
It's too white...make it brown!
每个人都要咖啡色  咖啡色...
Everyone wants only brown brown...
妈妈你看...这个小偷!
Mom look...thief!
就吃一块  妈妈
One sweet ladoo mom!
好吧，就吃一块
Ok my darling...have one
你真讨厌...
You're sick...
你很快就会变成一个拉杜球了
you are going to become a ladoo very soon
你就吃吧...多吃点...
Eat eat...eat more...
你很快就会撑死自己
you all are going to die very soon
Sapna 住口
Sapna quiet
你吃你的就行了
you should eat what you like
没错
Exactly
自从你加入了那个新的舞蹈班... 就开始...
This new fad of brown bread... egg whites...
热衷于什么黑面包...蛋清...
all started since you joined this new dance class...
还有那个...那个什么“查兹”舞!
that...that jhaaaz dance!
有什么好笑的？
What's so funny?
我受不了了...太好笑了...
I can't control it...it's too funny...
妈妈...你刚说什么... 什么舞? 什么舞蹈班?
Mama...say... what dance? What class?
什么舞蹈班?
Which class?
吃你的煎蛋卷吧
Eat your omelette
哪里有煎蛋卷? 这儿只有烤面包和薄饼
Where's the omelette? There's only toast and parantha here
来 爸爸...我们一起来跳“查兹”舞!
Come on Dad... let's do the jhaaaz dance!
Sapna...煎蛋卷
Sapna...your omelette
妈妈  不是“查兹”舞
Mom it is notjhaaaz dance...
是爵士舞
it is jazz dance
查兹...
Jaazz...
查...查兹...
J...Jhazz...
查兹...查兹...
Jaazzz...Jazz...
小心点... 包得严实些...
Aye careful... pack properly...
夫人... 是要像包“衣物”那样包吗?
Ma'am... It has to be gipt packed?
不是“衣物”... 是礼物...
Not 'gipt'... it's GIFT...
衣物...衣物...
Gipt...gipt...
无所谓了...
Never mind...
Satish... 我们的车有空吗?
Satish... is the car free?
我今天有很多点心的订单...
I have a lot of orders for sweets today...
你为什么非要去呢？整天送这些..
Why do you need to go? Send Ram u..
车我要开去开会啊...
I need to go for a meeting...
很高兴见到你 Shashi...
Nice to see you Shashi...
上次的点心球非常棒!
The ladoos were excellent the last time!
谢谢
Thank you
进来吧...
Come in...
下星期再多送些过来
Will need more ladoos next week as well
别让她看见，先给我吃一颗
Give me one ladoo before she sees
下一站, 摩登社区
Next, Modern Colony
好的，夫人
Yes madam
你好...请进
Hello... come in
抱歉我迟到了一会儿
Sorry I'm a little late
没关系
No problem at all
来...我们都来尝尝
Come... let's all taste the ladoos
真是太好吃了!
They are really excellent!
你的手艺真是太好了!
You've done a great job!
抱歉
Excuse me
Satish...
今天的点心球大受好评啊!
the ladoos were a super hit today!
每个人都喜欢...
Everyone loved...
我现在很忙... 一会儿再说好吗?
I'm busy right now... can we talk later please?
Saga r.
我跟你说过多少次了...不准这样
How many times have I told you... not to do this
你干什么!
What are you doing!
Sapna呢?
Where's Sapna?
你先跳一个迈克尔.杰克逊的舞
First do that Michael Jackson thing
告诉我
Tell me
你先跳！
First do!
先跳! 先跳!
First do! First do!
行了吧?
OK?
Sapna在哪儿?
Where's Sapna?
她去 Rupal 家学习去了
She's gone to Rupal's house... to study
要考试了?
What exam?
一定有什么测验吧？
Must be some test vest...
没有考试 妈妈...是去“我想要我的咖啡”去了!
No test vest mama... Cafe Coffee Day!
你居然泄秘了...
You've let out the secret...
你姐姐会怎么收拾你呢?
what will Sapna do to you now?
她和她的同伴去“我想要我的咖啡”了...
She's gone to Cafe Coffee Day with her friends...
她还喝了冰咖啡
she's having cold coffee
你是不是很生气啊?
Aren't you gotten angry?
没有啊...
Not 'gotten'...getting...
我不生气啊
I am not getting angry..-
你想干吗?
what to do?
她还穿了超短裙...
She's worn a really short skirt...
至少她有穿裙子!
At least she has worn a skirt!
还有很多男生一起呢!
There are boys with her too!
幸运的男生!
Lucky boys!
你不觉得有问题吗?
You don't have a problem with any of this?
我什么都听不到了
I can't hear anything
干嘛?
What?
你裙子上洒了冰咖啡哦
There's some cold coffee on your skirt
你去哪儿了?
Where have you been?
学习去了
5tudyil19
和谁?
With whom?
和 Rupal
With Ru pal
你就不能在家学习吗?
Can't you study at home?
你觉得你能辅导我的...
You think you can teach me...
英国文学课吗?
English Literature?
哦...咖喱真不错!
Wow... great curry!
感谢上帝，我没有在外面吃饭...
Thank god I didn't eat out...
给我再加点凉菜吧...
Give me that chilly pickle...
Shashi...
你还是别做这些点心球了吧
you should stop making those Iadoos vadoos
我就这么一个乐趣
I have just one passion..
你也要我放弃?
You want me to give that up too?
那就给我一个...
Then give me...
Shashi的经典点心球!
one Shashi Special Laden!
你的手艺应该我一个人独享
Only I should eat your food...
干嘛也给别人吃呢?
why should others enjoy it?
如果我做得不好吃...
If I didn't cook well...
你都不会想回家了，是吧?
...you wouldn't even bother to come home, right?
我要开很重要的会议...
I've important meetings to attend to...
不能浪费时间
these talks take time
和我说话没意思了是吧?
Talking to me is not important right?
哦，我忘了...
Oh I forget...
只有用英语交流才有意思
'important talks' happen only in English
何必要浪费时间来说话呢?
Why waste time talking?
不!不!不!
No! No! No!
爸爸你怎么能这样做？
Dad how could you do this? Please!
Sapna...
发生什么事了?
What happened?
Hello
Satish... 怎么了?
Satish... What happened?
为什么Sapna大喊大叫?
Why is Sapna yelling?
Shashi...我去不了PTA（家长会）了
Shashi...I won't be able to go to the PTA meeting
你怎么能这样?
How can you do this?
难怪她会发脾气...
No wonder she is angry...
你跟她说你陪她去...
Told her you will go with her...
我?
Me?
我怎么能...
How can I...
怎么不能? 你不也是家长吗?
What do you mean by how? Aren't you a parent too?
那我去了说什么?
What will I say there?
别傻了 Shashi...
Don't be silly Shashi...
你又不是去丛林冒险... 是去学校...
you're not going into a jungle... it's a school...
他们不会吃了你的
they're not going to eat you up
我得挂了，再见
Now I have to go... bye
Sapna，我会和你去...
I will come with you...
不需要...
There is no need...
我会说你病了，爸爸出差了
I will tell them you're ill and Dad's not in town
为什么要说病了?直接说我死了不更好
Why ill? Tell them I'm dead
不要开玩笑了，妈妈
Don't be dramatic mom
你甚至不知道PTA是什么意思?
Do you even know what PTA means?
是的...
No...
我也许是不知道PTA是什么...
I may not know the meaning of PTA...
但是我肯定知道家长会是什么
but I certainly know the meaning of a parent
在我真的生气之前...
Now before I get really angry...
赶紧去准备吧
90 get ready
哪一间是你的教室? 7A...这一个?
Which one is your classroom? 7A...this one?
哪个凳子是你的?
Which one is your seat?
不是凳子...是座位...在倒数第二排
Not seat...desk...second last row
你怎么坐得那么靠后?
You sit so far back?
没什么大不了的... 快走啦...
It doesn't make a difference... come on...
真的太靠后了...
That's really far back...
嗨 Sapna...
Hi Sapna...
嗨 Rupal!
Hi Rupal!
你好 你好!
Hello hello!
我是 Neelam...
I'm Neelam...
Rupal的妈妈
commonly known as Ru pal's mother these days
我是...Sapna 的...妈妈...Shashi
I'm...Sapna mother...Shashi
很高兴遇到你 Shashi
How nice to meet you Shashi
但有件事我得向你诉诉苦水了
But I have a bone to pick with you
每次Rupal去你们家做客
Every time that Rupal comes to eat at your house
回家就会跟我说
she comes back home and tells me
我应该好好地跟你学习一下烹饪
I have to learn how to cook from you
没有啦...你的饭菜也做得很...
No aunty...even your food is...
可口的!
fantabulous!
真是个甜蜜的小谎言
What a sweet little liar
但是你应该邀请我去一次你们家 Shashi...
But you must invite me home soon Shashi...
我们可以坐下来好好聊聊这两个小丫头
then you and I can sit and gossip about these Siamese twins
好啊...好啊  阿姨...
Yes...yes aunty...
请来我们家... 任何时间都行!
please come... anytime!
妈妈,你不是想去洗手间吗?
Mom, you wanted to use the loo right?
很高兴认识你 Shashi
So nice to meet you Shashi
Bye... 回头见
Bye... see you soon.
loo 是什么?
What loo?
来吧 来吧 来吧...
Come come come...
请进来坐... 我马上回来...
please sit inside... I'll be just a minute...
这是你的英语老师?
Is this your English teacher?
是的...文森特神父...我的班主任...
Yes...Father Vincent... my class teacher...
Sapna...
Yes Sapna...
你好吗?
How are you?
你是 God bole 女士吧？
Mrs. God bole right'?
很高兴认识你
Pleasure to meet you
你也好吧，God bole女士?
How's Mr. God bole?
很好...非常好
Fine...very fine
那么...Sapna...
So...Sapna...
我们从哪儿开始呢?
what should we start with?
上次PTA时我和God bole先生讨论了...
As I had discussed with Mr. Godbole at the last PTA...
Sapna的表现一直很棒
Sapna's performance continues to be excellent...
先生...不好意思...神父...
Sir...sorry... father...
我的英语不好
my English not good
如果你不介意
If you don't mind...
我们能不能用印地语交谈?
...can we talk in Hindi?
当然可以 God bole女士...
Of course Mrs. God bole...
印地语是我们的母语
Hindi is our national Language...
我们本应该用印地语说的
we should all speak in it...
但是...我的印地语不太好...
but...my Hindi not very good...
你看行吗?
is that okay?
没问题啊!
No problem!
我来自Kottayam区
I am from Kottayam district you see...
Kottayam... 是喀拉拉邦吗?
Kottayam... that's in Kerala right?
那里的香蕉片很有名的对吧?
It's famous for its banana wafers right?
是的，你喜欢吗?
Do you like them?
非常喜欢
Very m uch!
下次我回去的时候
Next time I go I...
给你带一...大包过来
I'll bring back a big packet of chips for you
她的成绩...还好吧？
Is she doing well in her studies?
当然...
Of course...
她是我们班前五名
she is one of the top 5 students of our class
要是她能在物理上再多多努力...
She could rank first...
她就能得全班第一
if she showed more interest in Physics
她的英语好不好？
But is her English good?
她的英语非常好
Her English is excellent
Godbole夫人 ...她是我们最优秀的学生之一
Mrs. Godbole... she is one of our brightest students
那她懂得礼貌吗？
But is she respectful?
和大家相处得好吗？
Does everyone like her?
Sapna....你没跟你妈妈说过你的那个粉丝俱乐部吗？
Sapna...you haven'! told your mum about your fan club?
Godbole夫人，我想和你谈谈...
Bu Mrs. Godbole, I wanted to talk to you about...
根据学校的测验比赛结果
...this inter-school quiz competition
Sapna已被选为...
Sapna has been chosen...
她被学校选为...
Sapna has 'chooser? for the school"
她选...
been 'choosed'...
被选
Has been chosen!
被选！我告诉过你我的印地语不好了
I warned you about my Hindi
她每天需要多在...学校呆一个小时...
She will need to stay back an extra hour in school...
来进行...练习...
for practice sessions...
老师...我已经跟我爸爸说过了...
Sir...l have already spoken to my dad about this...
完全没有问题的
and there is no problem
是的，但你还没有告诉你妈妈...
Yes but you haven't spoken to your mum...
夫人，我需要您的同意
Ma'am, I need your permission please
完全没有问题，神父...
Not a problem father...
我们学校一定会赢的
our school must win
虽然那家咖啡馆的营业额会有所影响
Although the Coffee Day business will suffer a bit
谢谢你 Godbole夫人 ...
Thank you Mrs. Godbole...
希望下次PTA还能见到你
I'll see you at the next PTA meeting?
不要忘了香蕉片哦
And don't forget the banana chips
当然不会...
Of course not...
谢谢你，先生
Thank you sir
一切都进展得很顺利吧？
Everything went well right?
香蕉片！
Banana chips!
神父又不是你叔叔？
Is Father Vincent your uncle?
可他很客气啊
Father Vincent was so kind
又谦和...
...so polite...
谈吐幽默...
he said something in jest...
我也是顺着他的意思说的啊
and I went along with it
他似乎也并不介意...
He didn't seem to mind at all...
他用印地语和我交谈...
he made me feel so comfortable...
让我感觉很舒服
by talking in Hindi
但用印地语和他交谈...
And you made him feel so uncomfortable...
你让他觉得不舒服啊...
...by talking in Hindi
Sapna是好孩子吗...
"ls Sapna a good girl...
大家都爱她吗...
does everyone love her"...
还有为什么开“我想要我的咖啡”的玩笑啊
And why joke about Cafe Coffee Day...
爸爸本来应该去的...
Dad should have been there...
而你甚至用印地语...
and you were talking in Hindi...
与鲁巴尔的母亲交谈
even to Rupal's mother
每次我都要在旁边为你解答
Each time I had to answer for you
发生什么事了？
What happened?
考试没考好？
Failed her exams?
是我没搞好
I'm the one who's failed
什么意思？
Meaning?
我让她丢脸了
I have embarrassed her today
所有的孩子们都会觉得他们的父母经常给自己丢脸
All teenagers feel their mom and dad are an embarrassment
不是父母...
Not mom and dad...
只有母亲
just mom
你为什么这么生气？
Why are you so upset?
告诉我...
Tell me...
你为什么愿意和我结婚？
why did you marry me?
我能说什么呢...一看到你，我就迷上了！
What can I say... one look at you and I was hooked!
还有水吗？
Isn't there any water?
你为什么不娶一个摩登女郎呢？
Why didn't you marry a modern woman?
如果我真的这么想，怎么可能还会结婚...
If I gave it so much thought why would I get married at all...
开个玩笑，Shashi...拜托...
It's a joke Shashi... come on...
你今天怎么了？
What's come over you?
无论我如何努力...
No matter how hard I try...
仍然还是惹你们厌烦
I just can't seem to please anyone
拜托，Sapna只是一个孩子
Sapna's just a child
那你呢？
And you?
你好...
Hello...
马努！
Mann!
嗨，你好，最近怎么样？
Hi...how are you?
是的，我知道你经常与你妹妹联系...
Yes I know you sisters chat regularly...
到现在才想起我
but what about me
在纽约怎么样？
So how is New York?
什么时候回来印度？
When are you coming to India?
上次你和蕾希一起来的时候...
Last time when you came along with Radha...
我们在一起玩得多么快乐啊
what a wonderful time we had
还有那个...还好吧？
So how is...
米拉？
Meera...?
什么！
What!
日期定在什么时候？
The date's been fixed?
在纽约结婚？！
Wedding in New York!
你和Shashi说说吧...
Speak to Shashi...
我简直不敢相信...
I can't believe it...
我们要去纽约了！
We're going to New York!
还让不让我睡觉啊...这么吵...
Can't sleep...so much noise...
傻瓜...醒醒吧...
Aye dumbo... wake up...
我们要去纽约了！
we're going to New York!
马努阿姨给我们寄了机票...
Manu aunty is sending tickets for us...
她太好了...是吧 妈妈？
so sweet of her...right mom?
对不起...妈妈...
Sorry mom...
原谅我吧...
forget about it please...
就忘了它吧...
just forget it...
我们要去纽约了！
we are going to New York!
你不用上学吗？
Not going to school?
表姐米拉要结婚了
Cousin Meera is getting married
在美国的纽约...简直太酷了！
To an American in New York... how cool!
那里确实很冷
It must be very cold there
妈妈...即使那里很热，你也感受不到
Mom... even it if was hot, you couldn't come
为什么呢？
Why?
你没有护照啊
You don't have a passport
一定要有护照吗？
You have to make a passport?
是的，一定要...
Yes you have to...
明天我就去办理签证手续...
Tomorrow I'll start the visa procedures...
首先是你的...你得先去
first is yours... since you need to leave before us
那我们呢？
And us?
我们过后去
We will go later
为什么？
Why?
我跟你说过...
I've told you...
我不想一个人去
I don't want to go alone
那我和你一起去...
I'll come with you...
坐飞机哦
on the plane
为什么要这样安排？
What's this alone valone?
你，Sagar和我，我们三个一起
You, Sagar and me will travel together
会很好玩的...
We will have great fun...
让妈妈先去
let mummy go ahead
她还要帮助马努阿姨操办婚礼...
She needs to help Manu aunty with the wedding...
很多事要做
really boring work
晚些去的话，直接就可以玩了
We'll join them later and just have fun
不行...爸爸
What...no Dad!
你不管你的测验比赛了？
What about your quiz competition?
你想让你的团队输掉吗？
You want to let your team down?
我没有任何比赛
I don't have any quiz competition
我可以和妈妈一起走吧
I can go with mummy
行啊...你就等着被学校开除了...
Fine... you'll be thrown out of school...
然后就只能在家里做做小点心
...you can sit at home and make ladoos
干嘛？
What?
我从来没有单独旅行过...
I've never travelled alone...
我怎么应付得了？
how will I manage?
怎么会是单独旅行？
What alone!
在飞机上，有上百人会与你一起
A hundred people will be with you on the flight
让我带着Sagar...
Let me take Sagar...
不，这不行...
No it's not a good idea...
你就真的应付不过来了
you won't be able to manage
难道我现在做得不好吗？
Don't I do it here?
但是，那是在美国...是国外...
But that's America... it's a foreign land...
你甚至连英语都说不好
you can't even speak English well
你是不是很开心...
Will you be happy...
三个星期都见不到我了？
3 weeks without me?
Shashi 如果我是你...
Shashi If I was you...
我现在已经在机场了
I would be at the airport right now
妈妈 ...我怎么能去？
Maaji...how do I go?
这几天的事...
It's a matter of a few days...
过段时间大家就会一起过去的
everyone will join you anyway
她是你唯一的姐姐...
She is your only sister...
在那边独自一人...
she's all alone there...
操办着她的第一次婚礼...
first wedding in the family...
还有谁能过去帮她？
who else will she turn to for help?
家里还有我啊...
And I'm here anyway...
有麻烦吗？
Problem?
是啊...一个真正的大麻烦
Yes... a really big problem
你没有我在能搞定吗？
Will you manage without me?
没问题....少玩些游戏啊 ...
Yes...few Beyblades...
那些电子游戏...
that Tron game...
象“外星英雄” ...
Ben 10...
还有“风火轮车”...
and many Hot Wheels cars...
如果是这些，我都能搞定
if I get all this I will manage
接下来是什么动作？
And how do you do that thing?
啊，亲爱的...没有你，我的心感觉空荡荡
O my dear... my heart doesn't beat without you
我的心在抽搐
My heart...it feels a twitch
我如何能远渡重洋？
How do I go to a foreign land?
我的心...
My heart...
我的心在颤抖在颤抖
My heart trembles...quivers
我很担心
I am afraid
啊，亲爱的...没有你，我的心感觉空荡荡
O my dear... my heart doesn't beat without you
我的心...感到抽搐
My heart...it feels a twitch
我如何能远渡重洋？
How do I go to a foreign land?
你拥抱你的同事都是这么深情吗？
Do you embrace all your colleagues so fondly?
只是一个友好的拥抱 Shashi
It was a hug Shashi
你们两个看起来很亲密啊
Are the two of you very close?
这只是打招呼的一种方式...
That's just a way of saying hello...
并不意味着我们很亲密
it doesn't mean we are close
每个人都这样拥抱...这很正常！
Everybody hugs... it's normal!
我们已经很亲密...
We are close right...
所以反而没有这样的拥抱了是吧？
maybe that's why we never hug!
有时候，我的心跳加速
Sometimes my heart beats faster
我的眼睛跳动
My left eye flickers
你会遗忘我吗...我不知道
Will you forget me... I wonder
你从头到脚我都熟悉
I know you through and through
我比你自己还了解你
I know you more than you
你的眼睛跳动吗...我不知道
Will your eye wander... I wonder
那么，女士...你的工作是？
So ma'am...what do you do?
制作...制作点心...
Making...making snacks...
点心？
Snacks?
那你知道你不能把食品类
You know you are not allowed to bring food articles
带去美国吧？
into the United States of America?
食品类
Food...food articles...
我的英语...不好...
My English...weak...
既然你的英语不好...
So ma'am how will you manage in our country...
你怎么还到美国去呢？
if you don't know English?
你还不是不懂印地语就来我们国家了？
Like you are managing in our country without knowing Hindi!
这些日日夜夜
These nights these days
你的言语 你的行动
Your words and ways
我都珍藏心底
I will miss them so...
你的点点滴滴
Your slights and spite
你紧紧拥抱着我的方式
The way you hold me tight
让我无限怀想
Makes me pine for more...
你为什么不阻止我？
Why don't you stop me?
不要让我独自离开
O don't let me go!
一提到你...
One mention of you...
我担心...担心...日夜想念着你
I worry...I'm wary... I think of you...
妈妈，快点，要迟到了！
Mama come fast... it's late!
我的心脏...
My heart...
我的心在颤抖...颤抖
My heart trembles...quivers
我担心
I am afraid
妈妈...
Mom...
在印度不哭就不能道别是吧？
not possible to say goodbye without crying in India, right?
她哭得这么厉害
She's crying so much
Shashi...
当移民局的人问你  ...
when the immigration guys ask you...
你这次过来的目的是什么？
"What is the purpose of your visit?"
你会怎么说？
what will you say?
我去参加姐姐家的婚礼
"I am going to sister's place to attend wedding"
好的！
Good!
那么你要逗留多长时间？
And "What's the duration of your stay?"
我要...
I am going to...
我要留在我姐姐那里...
I am going to stay in my sister's place...
这样你会被遣送回来的
Looks like you'll be sent right back!
为什么？
Why?
我问的是... 多长时间
Didn't I tell you... DURATION!
多长时间
DURATION!
对不起对不起...
Sorry sorry...
5个星期...
5 weeks...
走吧走吧！
Let's go!
你做什么？
What are you doing?
抱也不是，不抱也不是啊？
If I hug it's a problem, if I don't it's a problem!
纽约...
New York...
是靠窗的座位吗？
window seat?
难道没有印地语的表格吗？
Don't they have this form in Hindi?
我可以帮你填
I can fill it out for you
去美国吗？
America?
是的...我的外甥女要结婚了
Yes...my niece is getting married
一路顺风
All the best
请打开你的包...
Open your bag...
不允许带水上飞机的
no water allowed
但是旅途时间很长啊...
But it's a long journey...
飞机上有水
You will get water inside
吃的也不允许带
Eatables are not allowed either
就一盒行吗？
Just one box?
对不起，女士...
Sorry ma'am...
好了
Alright?
Satish...他们没收了我的水壶...
Satish... they took away my water bottle...
我在飞机上了...
I'm inside the plane...
Sapna 睡着了吗？
is Sapna asleep?
对不起，夫人...
Excuse me ma'am...
请你关掉你的手机
can you please turn off your cell phone
对不起
sorry
没事...你自己收着就行了
No it's fine...you can keep it
水...
Water...
你可以按铃
You can ring the bell
请你拿杯水给这位夫人好吗？
Can you get the lady a glass of water please?
接下来的18个小时...这个按钮随时可以为你服务
The next 18 hours... this button is at your service
你可以...
You can...
自信些，自然些
confidently, definitely, surely
放心大胆
absolutely shamelessly
一遍又一遍地按
press this button again and again
你看看...神奇吧！
See... magic!
女士，你要素食还是荤食？
Ma'am, veg or non veg?
素...食
Veg...veg...
要红葡萄酒还是夏敦埃酒呢？
Would you like some Chardonnay or Merlot with your meal?
一杯葡萄酒对健康有益
One glass of wine is good for health
干杯！
Cheers!
味道很好
It's good stuff
怎么了？
What's the matter?
只有一部印地语电影...
Just one Hindi movie here...
可我在电视上已经看过了
I've seen it on TV
还有50个英语频道...
And 50 English channels...
这里...看...
Here...look...
同样的画面...
same picture...
同一部电影...
same film...
没必要戴耳机了
there's no need for that
我要跟我父亲说话（科幻大片《源代码》）
I need to talk to my father
上尉，是谁炸了火车？
Captain, who bombed the train
我不知道是谁炸了火车
I don't know who bombed the train
那回去，再试一次
Then go back and try again
“不！” “不！” “不！”
No! No! No!
不要胡说...
Stop this cow dung...
我们就从爆炸开始调查...
Let's start with the bomb...
对不起
Excuse me...
你是恐怖分子吗？
are you a terrorist?
我们打算睡觉呢...
We are trying to sleep here...
我会去的，但...
I will go but...
我去我姐姐家参加婚礼的...
I am going to sister's place to attend wedding...
请出示护照
Passport please...
入境登记表...
Immigration form...
请看着镜头
Please look into the camera ma'am
看着这个镜头
Please look into the camera...
你到访美国的目的是什么？
What is the purpose of your visit to the United States?
什么？
What?
你到访...美国...的目的...是什么？
What...is...the...purpose...of... your...visit...to the United States?
我姐姐要参加我的婚礼
My sister is attending my wedding
什么？
What?
啊，你是为了参加一个婚礼！
Ah you're here to attend a wedding!
是
Yes
谢谢
Thank you
你到访美国的...- 我是来帮助美国的
What is the purpose... - To help the United States of America
你说什么？
Sorry?
啊...你知道...
Yeah...you know...
花一些美元...
to spend some dollars...
帮助恢复你们的经济
help recover your economy
你不想要吗？我可以回去...
You don't want it? I can go back...
我要去姐姐家参加婚礼
I am going to sister's place to attend wedding!
我太蠢了   - 听着...
How dumb am I... - Listen...
不要让这些人吓唬你...
Don't let these people scare you...
现在该是他们害怕我们的时候了
it's time for them to get scared of us
这是你第一次来美国吧
This is your first trip to the US...
第一次是独一无二的
and first times happen only once
每个第一次的经验都会很特别
Every first experience is special...
所以 好好享受吧...
so enjoy...
自信地，放心大胆地
surely, definitely, confidently!
一路顺风
All the best!
Shashi 阿姨！
Shashi aunty!
妈妈...你到了吗？
Mom... you've reached?
我在车上！
I'm in the car!
你怎么样？
How are you?
但愿孩子们没有烦你，我希望...
The kids aren't troubling you I hope...
嗨妈妈！
Hi mama!
Sagar！
Sagar!
阿姨...
Aunty...
不要担心Sapna，Sagar和叔叔了
no more worrying about Sapna, Sagar and uncle...
你在纽约了...我们要尽情玩乐
you're in New York... we're going to have a blast!
纽约很多摩天大楼啊，对不对？
New York has really tall buildings, right?
我从飞机上看到了
Saw them from the plane...
Shashi...那是曼哈顿...
Shashi...that's Manhattan...
人...帽子...晒黑？
Man...hat...tan?
“Man”是指...
'Man' means...
比如我
aadmi...
“Hat”指
'Hat'...means
帽子
topi
妈妈...在印地语里面什么是“顿”？
Mom... what's 'tan' in Hindi?
“顿”...是指...
'Tan'...means...
多普棋！
dhoop ki chaap!
曼...帽子...多普棋...
Aadmi...topi...dhoop ki chaap...
曼哈顿！明天我带你去
Manhattan! Tomorrow I'll take you
谢谢你 Shashi...
Thank you Shashi...
你说谢谢你？
Thank you...?
那我就...不客气了
Ok...welcome
我知道你决定过来很不容易
I know it wasn't easy for you to come...
但我除了你谁也没有了
but who do I have except you
阿尼尔去世已有10年
It's been 10 years since Anil passed away
我真的很想念他...
I really miss him...
自私的家伙！
selfish fellow!
我现在一切都要靠自己
I have to do everything on my own now
马努...
Manu...
我看着你就感到骄傲...
I look at you and I feel so proud...
想想我们从哪儿开始的
to think of where we started... and where you are now!
还记得我们在印度的中学时代吗？
Remember our Hindi medium school?
我们一句英语也不会...
We couldn't speak a single word of English...
一句也不会！
not a word!
看看你现在...
And look at you now...
你在美国有一个了不起的职业
you have a great career here in America...
独自抚养两个女儿
taken care of 2 girls all by yourself
是阿尼尔...阿尼尔...
Anil... Anil...
如果不是他激励着我...
If he hadn't motivated me...
我肯定还在原地踏步
I would have remained the same
我想他想得发疯...
I miss him so terribly...
但感谢上帝，你来了！
but thank god you're here!
阿姨 这个好华丽！
Aunty this is gorgeous!
Shashi 眼光真不错！
Wonderful choice Shashi!
帽子...晒黑的人...
Hat...man...with a tan
曼哈顿
Manhattan
摩天大楼，哦，我的上帝！
Touching heaven, oh my god!
曼哈顿
Manhattan.
欢乐聚集的大道
New avenues of joy
充满梦想的商店
Shops full of dreams
每到一站，都有一个新的惊喜
A new surprise, at every stop
在你的左边是Prada
To your left is Prada
在你的右边是ZARA
To your right is Zara
乔治阿玛尼，感谢上帝，今天是星期五！
Giorgio Armani, Thank God it's Friday!
Gucci和范思哲（Versace）
Gucci and Versace,
吉米.乔科，纪梵希
Jimmy Choc, Givenchy
迪赛，迪奥，地摊，GAP和Bloomingdale
Diesel, Dior, Hokey Pokey, Gap and Bloomingdale
路易.威登
Louis Vuitton
莫斯基诺
Moschino
华伦天奴...
Valentino...
满腹话语却又说不出来
So much to say yet speechless
熙熙攘攘却又好似形单影只
All together, still alone
这样的城市，祝你好运！
What a city! Touch wood
第5,6,7,8大道
5,6,7,8 avenues
成千上万穿着各式鞋子的人
Million billion legs and shoes
五彩缤纷，纸醉金迷
Lots of colours, dollars dollars
吃喝玩乐
sense of pidlee poo
早餐全天供应
Breakfast is for all day
异性恋和同性恋都在街上大摇大摆
Straight and gay they all sway
列克星敦，麦迪逊，都让人眼花缭乱
and Lexington, and Madison, it's all so ooh!
星冰乐
Frappuccino
Mochaccino
卡布奇诺...
Cappuccino...
你那样做的时候还得唱“巴勒巴勒”
You gotto say balle balle while you do that...
巴勒巴勒巴勒！
Balle balle balle balle!
阿姨...你都没怎么吃
Aunty...you're not eating
食物不好吃吗？
food's not good?
不是啊，这个薄饼挺好吃的
This parantha is really good...
这是墨西哥食品...油炸玉米饼
It's Mexican food...Quesadilla...
不管是什么...它很好吃！
Whatever it is...it's good!
那是什么？她说什么？
What's that? What did she say?
她在批评你呢
She just abused you
那告诉我嫁妆的事吧，你们会给我什么？
So tell me about the dowry, what are you giving me?
- 给你什么？- 我们又不是在买你...
- What am I giving you? - We are not buying you...
不应该这样的
that's not how it works
应该是男方给女方嫁妆
The boy gives the girls family the dowry
要给很多很多的彩礼
And lots and lots of gifts
所以我要破产了？
So I'm going to go broke?
我不知道为什么，但我真的很困了
I don't know why but I'm really sleepy
那快去睡吧，亲爱的...
Go sleep my dear...
你还好吗？
Is that alright?
是的，当然
Yes of course
感觉很累...她肯定是太累了
I feel so bad... she must be so tired
时差还没倒过来
Must be the jet lag
您好 萨蒂什...
Hello Satish...
孩子们怎么样？
how are the kids?
他们去上学了吗？
Have they gone to school?
他们都带了盒饭吧？
Have they taken their lunch boxes?
你尽量早点回家吧
Please do try to get home early...
我在这里感觉有点怪...
I'm feeling a bit strange here...
没有你们在身边
without all of you...
Shashi...只管尽情享受吧...
Shashi...just enjoy yourself...
我要进电梯了...稍后再聊
I'm getting into an elevator... will talk later
睡得好吗？
Slept well?
对不起...我得去下办公室
Sorry...got to go to office for a bit
我会尽快回来
I'll try to be back as soon as possible...
然后我们讨论一下婚礼程序
we'll start on the wedding plans
开车要小心...
Drive carefully...
再见，亲爱的，再见！
Bye darling, see you!
阿姨早上好！
Good morning Aunty!
我给你做点早餐吧？
Should I make you some breakfast?
不用了，我有麦片粥
No I have cereal
你一个人在家时做什么呢？
What are you going to do by yourself?
我们能收看到印度ZEE TV的节目
We do have Zee TV Hindi but...
我有一个想法，你可以跟我一起去学校
I have an idea, why don't you come with me to college!
我去学校干什么
What will I do there?
我有2小时的课...
I have class for 2 hours...
你可以先在咖啡馆里坐坐...
and you can hang out at a cafe...
下课了我就来找你
and I'll come join you
你有现金吗？...零钱呢？
You got cash...change?
有的
Yes
不用担心...
And don't worry...
万一你走丢了...
in case you get lost...
如果你迷路了就打电话给我
if you do get lost just call me
不要担心，你去吧
Don't worry, go now
这里的公园是如此美丽...
The parks here are so beautiful...
华盛顿广场公园
Washington Square Park...
华盛顿...广场...公园...
Washington...Square...Park...
对了！
Good!
哇...你穿的衣服真漂亮！
Wow...that's a beautiful dress you're wearing!
这位女士也太粗鲁了...
Man: This lady is so rude...
可能今天不太愉快吧
must be having a bad day
我要一杯现磨咖啡...
Can I get a regular coffee...
和一份蓝莓松饼
and a blueberry muffin
这是你的收据...请到那边取餐...
Here's your receipt... please pick up your food over there...
好的...祝你愉快
Okay...have a nice day
下一个！
Next!
今天过得好吗，女士？
How you doing today ma'am?
我想要...
I want...
我问你今天过得好吗？
I asked how you were doing today
我...我...
Doing...I'm doing...
我就是...
I'm doing...
你得抓紧时间
You can't take all that time
后面还排了很长的队
I got a long line here
对不起...有什么吃的？
Sorry... what to eat?
你在开玩笑吧
Are you kidding me right now...
请快点  女士
please hurry up lady
素食...
Vegetarian...
素食很好
Vegetarian is fine...
但是你想吃什么？
what do you want to eat?
只要素食
Only vegetarian...
一个硬面包圈...一个三明治？
A bagel...a wrap...a sandwich?
三明治
Sandwich
里面要什么夹心？
And what kind of filling do you want inside?
要奶酪...
Do you want cheese...
西红柿...还是生菜？
tomatoes... lettuce"?
女士...你严重占用时间了
Lady...you're holding up my line...
这又不是火箭科学
this is not rocket science
奶酪？
Cheese?
好吧，奶酪...
Yes... cheese...
是的，奶酪！
Yes to cheese!
要喝什么吗？
Anything to drink?
水...
Water...
白水还是汽水？
Still or sparkling?
就是水
Only water
白水还是汽水？
Still or sparkling?
咖啡？
Coffee...?
美国风味？卡布奇诺？还是拿铁？
Americana'? Cappuccino? Latte?
女士...我赶时间
Lady...I ain't got all day...
美国风味？卡布奇诺？还是拿铁？
Americana'? Cappuccino? Latte?
雀巢咖啡
'Nescoffee'
什么？
What?
雀巢咖啡
'Nescoffee'
是的，我们有很好的咖啡...
Yes we have nice coffee...
我们在曼哈顿有最好的咖啡
we have the best coffee in Manhattan
我就给你美式咖啡好了
I'll just give you an Americana
小杯还是中杯？
Small or medium?
小...杯
Small
小杯，确定吗？
Small. Is that it?
10.2美元
$10.20
10美元...
10 dollars...
至少你该说声谢谢！
Hello...the least you could do is say thank you...!
对不起...谢谢你...
Sorry...thank you...
愚蠢的白痴！
Stupid idiot!
对不起...
Sorry...
我可不去清洗！
I am not cleaning that up!
没事的
Don't bother...
这个蠢女人
What a stupid woman
女士...
Madam...
你的咖啡...
your coffee...
咖啡馆里的
from the coffee shop
那家咖啡馆不好...
Cafe not good...
女营业员...不是很好
woman...not nice!
阿姨！
Aunty!
稍候...我来了...
Wait...I'm coming...
小心...这么大的巴士
Be careful...such a big bus
在四个星期内学会说英语的...太假啦！
Learn to speak English in four weeks... what a con!
怎么可能有人在短短的4个星期内就学会说英语的呢？
Can anyone learn to speak English in just four weeks?
开笑话，对吗？
Joke right?
你今天玩得开心吗？
Did you have fun today?
请检查号码，然后再试一次
Please check the code and try again
Shashi Shashi...！
Shashi...Shashi...!
亲爱的，给我看候选的智者
Sweetheart get me that back up panditji
还有乐师
and those musicians?
明天我们要去见一个印度教祭司
We have to meet the Hindu priest tomorrow
美国的印度教祭司？
American Hindu priest?
不...他们也是印度人...
No...they're all our people...
美国的印度教牧师...很酷的想法，妈妈
American Hindu Priest... cool idea mom
他们在婚礼上唱些什么？
What do they chant at weddings?
“bhurbuvasvaha嗡”什么的...
'Om bhurbuvasvaha' what else...
不对...这是Gayatri真言！
No way...that's the Gayatri Mantra!
妈妈！- 我尽力了...
Mom! - I tried...
你明天去见祭司吗？
Will you meet the priest tomorrow?
好啊 - 他说纯粹的印地语
Yes definitely - He speaks in pure Hindi
这个电话号码清单你留着...
Keep this list of phone numbers with you...
膳食供应商，装饰工，祭司等人..
caterers, decorators, priest etc...
打电话时，普纳的城市区号是020
and just like you dial the city code of '020' in Pune...
在这儿你要拔212
...you will need to dial the code '212' here
太棒了！
Fabulous!
这么多年没吃过这么地道的东西了
Such good food after so many years
家里的钥匙给你...
House keys...
如果你想出去走走
in case you feel like stepping out
祭司来了
The priest is here
这是我的妹妹 Shashi...
This is my younger sister Shashi...
你可以和她讨论一切
you can discuss everything with her
好的
Sure
欢迎致电纽约语言中心 ...有什么需要帮忙的吗？
Welcome to NYLC...how can I help you?
你好...
Hello...
英语辅导班吗？
English tuition?
是的
Yes English classes
请问你是？
Who am I speaking to?
你叫什么名字？
What is your name please?
L. ..Shashi...
L...Shashi...
Shaashi 吗？
Sha...Shaashi...?
好 Shaashi 需要帮忙吗？
Well Shaashi what can I do for you?
请问如何报读？
How to...join class?
我们今天有个“LSE4”的课程开班了
Well we have a 'LSE4' class that starts today...
“LSE6”下周开始...
an 'LSE6' class starting next week...
“LSE8”，下月起...
and an 'LSE8' class that starts next month...
LIC？
LIC...?
哦...对不起...
Oh...sorry...
LSE4就是在4周内学会用英语交谈
'LSE' is Learn to speak English in 4 weeks...
LSE6是在6周内学会用英语交谈
'LSE6' is Learn to speak English in 6 weeks...
女士...对不起...
Madam...sorry...
慢点行吗？
slow...
抱歉，好的
sorry
“LSE4”班
The 'Learn to Speak English 4' class
是一个4周学会用英语交谈的课程...
is a 4 week class...
从今天开始上课
and it starts today
今天！
Today!
多少钱？
Money?
哦，你的意思是费用
Oh you mean the fee
要400美元，4周的课程
It's 400 dollars for the 4 week class
400美元？
400?
喂？
Hello?
欢迎致电纽约语言中心 ...有什么需要帮忙的吗？
Welcome to NYLC... how can I help you?
我是Shashi...
I Shashi...
请问地址是
address...?
如果你是坐地铁...
If you are taking the train...
在23号站下车
get off at the 23rd street station
就在艾恩大厦旁边...
It's near the Flat Iron building...
23号站   一张
23rd station...one ticket
等一下...
Wait...
地铁...去23号站？
Train...23rd station?
不，不，在那边站台上车
No no...on the other platform.
16号大街？
16th street?
23号大街后面是24号大街
After street no. 23, comes 24...
这就是说16是在那边
which means 16 is on that side...
数字，数字，到处都是数字
numbers numbers everywhere...
M.G.路...拉克西米路...
M.G. Road... Laxmi road...
他们为什么不能这样起名呢？
why can't they just have names like that
先生... 250号？
Sir...250 building?
是的，就是这里
Yes, this is it
是英语站...不...
English station...tuition?
是英语课吗？
English class?
Shaaashi 吗？
Shaaashi...?
欢迎来到“纽约语言中心”
Welcome to the "New York Language Centre"
来吧，请进..
Come in, come in...
请坐
take a seat
我的名字是大卫，大卫菲舍尔...
My name is David...David Fischer...
我是你的老师
and I'm your teacher
你好...
Hello...
好了...让我们继续...
Ok...let's continue...
...我...是...EVA ...
...I Eva...
我...来...墨西哥...
I...come...Mexico...
我的工作是保姆
I work like nanny
为一个美国家庭
I work like nanny...
当保姆
to American family
我会说西班牙语...
I speak Spanish...
他们的孩子，也讲西班牙语
the baby...speak Spanish
宝宝的妈妈很担心
The baby mama so worry
宝宝不会说英语
baby no speak English
她就对我说...去...
She say to me...go...
上英语课...
English class...
我 ...去...英语课！
I... go... English class!
伊娃,亲爱的...
Eva my darling...
让我们为宝宝的未来祈祷吧
let's pray for the baby's future, shall we?
我...皇后...
I Queens...
好可爱啊！
How lovely!
不...不...
No...no...
我靠着皇后生活
I live on the Queens
哦，你住在纽约的皇后区
You live in Queens, New York
你叫什么名字？
What is your name?
萨尔曼•可汗
Salman Khan
我来自拉合尔...
I first from Lahore...
从巴基斯坦
second from Pakistan
我
I--_
开出租车
drive taxi...
纽约的出租车
New York cab
但是，没有巴基斯坦的女孩会和出租车司机结婚...
But no Pakistani girl marry taxi driver...
请用英语！
English please!
我...这里...来...
I here...come...
英语学习...
English learn...
成为外国人
become foreigner
巴基斯坦女孩只愿意嫁给外国人
Pakistani girl only marry foreigner
有法式胡子的，象约翰尼•德普...
french beard, Johnny Depp...
萨尔曼...我希望你有一个美丽的巴基斯坦
Salman... I wish you a beautiful Pakistani
女孩...只要女孩
Girl sir...only girl
真无聊！
How boring!
我们继续
Moving on...
来自法国的绅士
the gentleman from France
大家好
Hello
我的名字是洛朗...
My name is Laurent...
法国人...
French...
我是个厨师
I'm cook...
...在酒店...
...in hotel...
我的英语不干净...
and my English not clean...
很脏
dirty
我学英语...
I learn English...
学好它
900d
不错不错！
Good good!
谢谢你，洛朗...
Thank you Laurent...
现在，轮到这位穿着美丽纱丽的女士...
And now the lady in the gorgeous sari...
坐...坐...
Sit...
坐着说？
Sit and talk?
我叫Shashi...
I Shashi...
来自那个印度
from the India
来自印度...
From India...
是的，先生...来自那个印度...
Yes sir... from the India...
不对，Shashi，不要加那个（the）...
No Shashi...not from 'the' India...
是来自印度！
from India!
你的工作是什么，Shashi？
And what do you do Shashi?
我也烹饪...
I also cooking...
烹饪...然后销售...
cooking...selling...
你在餐饮业？
Are you in the catering business?
小本生意
Small business...
就在家里而已...
in house only...
制作点心...
making snacks...
拉杜球！
ladoo!
拉杜吗？
Ladoo...?
拉杜球，圆圆的...
Ladoo...round round...
是一种甜点
It's a sweet...
我们班上有一个企业家！
We have an entrepreneur in the class!
企业家...
Entrepreneur...
意思是开创自己企业的人
is a person who runs his or her own business
Shashi...你是一个企业家！
Shashi...you are an entrepreneur!
这是一个单词还是一首诗？
Is that a word or a poem?
这是什么鸟语？
What kind of a language is this!
企...业...家...
Entre...pre...near
企业家！
Entrepreneur!
Shashi 我回家了...
Shashi I'm home...
你去哪儿了？
Where were you?
散步去了
Just for a walk...
你为什么要担心这么多？
Why are you worrying so much?
你有3个星期的自由时间，充分利用吧
You have 3 weeks of freedom left... make the most of it
可要你做这么多工作...
You're having to do so much work...
工作？什么工作？
Work? What work?
我给他们安排工作才对...
I'm making all of them work...
是老家伙才有的特殊待遇
the perks of being old
进展得怎么样了？
How is it going?
你知道他们在这里叫我什么吗？
You know what they call me here?
知道啊... Shaaashi
Yes...Shaaashi
不对
No...
企业家！
Entrepreneur!
你有在为大家做杜拉球吗，骑野家？
Have you been making Iadoos for everyone there?
我还以为断线了呢
I thought we got disconnected
你好...
Hello...
要喝水吗？
You want water?
谢谢你...
Thank you...
不客气
Welcome
谢谢你...
Thank you...
不客气
Welcome
那一天...
That day...
非常非常糟糕的一天
very very bad day
一切都错乱了...
Everything went wrong...
我也觉得...对不起...
I feel...sorry...
糟糕的一天！
Bad day!
我不会忘记你的脸
Me not forget your face
你的脸
Your face
上课...晚了！
Class..-late!
哦，是啊..
Oh, yeah..
A. .. E. .. L.. O. .还有 U. ..
A...E...l...O...U...
这些被称为元音字母
These are called vowels
伊娃...伊娃！
Eva...Eva!
这些是什么？
What are these called?
元音字母
Vowels
就像内脏
Just like bowels
不对，拉玛...
No Rama...
不是内脏！
not like bowels!
对不起，夫人...
Sorry madam...
先生...对不起，先生...
sir...sorry sir...
我只是说如何可以巧记...
I only saying for remembering purpose...
毛巾...
towels...
内脏...
bowels...
还有...元音字母！
and...vowels!
对吗？
Correct?
现在，当一个单词是以元音开头...
Now, when a word begins with a vowel...
比如说苹果...
like apple...
是以元音“a”开头...
begins with a vowel 'a'...
那么前边的冠词要用“an”
we say 'an' apple
an“橙子”
'An' orange...
an“白痴”
.An- idiot
因此，我...
So I...
就是an“eva”罗
an Eva?
不对..如果是个名字...或专有名词...
No...if it's a name... or a proper noun...
我们就只说，EVA ...
we just say Eva...
不说 an EVA ...
not an Eva...
或者 the 印度
or the India
明白吗？
Okay?
只是EVA ...只是拉玛
Just Eva...just Rama
说吧，Shashi？
Yes Shashi?
为什么印度不能说 the India
Why India not 'the India'
而美国
and why America
就要说成the United States of America？
"the United States of America"?
这是一个非常好的问题，Shashi...
That is a very good question Shashi...
我们以后会解答这个问题
and we will come to that once
我们现在讲名词的变形
we do the class on the various forms of nouns
女士，你问的这个问题多好啊！
What a question you asked madam!
大卫老师都回答不上来...
David sir had no answer...
他完全混乱了
full confusion
好问题...
Good question...
非常聪明...
very smart...
又睡觉了
Sleeping again
我们要比这些人更聪明...
We are smarter than these people...
我们那么努力，就只为了学这个该死的英语
we struggle only because of this bloody English...
否则我们早让他们见鬼去了
else we would have blown them away
你说什么呢？
What you say?
我说我去你那儿做客
I say I come to your parlour...
你给我免费剪头发...
you give me free hair cut...
然后我免费教你乌尔都语
and I teach you free Urdu
你来做客...
You come to parlour...
我绝对剃光你的头！
I shave your head!
辣妹啊...
Spicy noodle...
就像一条龙！
just like dragon!
对不起，我...
Excuse me...
你好...
hello...
什么是好的名字？
what is good name?
他说什么？
What did he say?
奇怪的家伙...怪异的家伙...
Strange fellow...weird fellow...
你说的英语还是泰米尔语？
Did you speak in English or in Tamil?
你问了个好问题
You ask good question
好吗？
Good?
非常好
Very good
谢谢
Thank you
能问个问题吗...我？
Ask question...me?
你？问我？
You? Me?
是的！
Yes!
OK！
OK!
喝杯咖啡...
Cup of coffee...
和我一起...现在？
with me...now?
回家...
House...
我...咖啡...
me...coffee...
再见！
bye!
- 好的，再见。- 再见。再见。
- Yeah, bye. - See you. Bye.
咖啡 Voffee 糖 Vugar
Coffee-Voffee Sugar-Vugar
纸 汽相 新闻 Vews
Paper-Vaper News-Vews
时钟 VOK 时间 VIME
Clock-Vok Time-Vime
运行 VUN 运行 VUN
Run-Vun Run-Vun
火车 徒劳的 传递 增值业务
Train-Vain Pass-Vass
晚上 私人类 增值业务
Late-Vate Class-Vass
友谊 Vendship 结合 自动售货机
Friendship-Vendship Bonding-Vending
我已经改变了视角
I've changed my point of view
周围的一切都是新的
Everything around is new
我很高兴和开心，哦，为什么呢？
I'm happy-vappy why, oh why?
因为我很忙碌充实，这就是为什么！
I'm busy-vusy that's why!
慢慢地，慢慢地，稳步前进
Slowly, slowly, steadily
我正在努力学习新的语言
I'm learning-vearning a new language
慢慢地，慢慢地，稳步前进
Slowly, slowly, steadily
我正在努力学习新的语言
I'm learning-vearning a new language
非凡的！
Extraordinary!
如此激情！
This passion!
从早上到中午！
Morning noon!
非凡的！
Extraordinary!
如此激情！
This passion!
从早上到中午！
Morning noon!
一切尽在印式英语！
It's all about English Vinglish!
从早晨到中午，印式英语！
Morning noon English Vinglish!
- 早上好。- 早上好。
- Good morning. - Good morning.
早餐准备好了！
Breakfast is ready!
我今天在家休息
I've taken the day off
那我该如何去上课呢？
How do I go to class today?
你干嘛为了我呆在家里啊？
Why did you take the day off for me?
到时为了婚礼，你还要请假
You'll need to take leave for the wedding too...
你干嘛这样说
What do you mean?
我已经没有好好陪你了
I haven't spent any time with you...
我们要好好聊聊
we have so much to catch up on
还记得阿尼尔妈妈给我的那条项链吗？
Remember the necklace Anil's mother had given me?
我已经把它分成两条了，一条给米拉...
I've divided them equally, one for Meera...
一条给茹阿达
and one for Radha
我还发现了一个非常漂亮的手链...
What a beautiful bracelet I found...
你在找什么？
what are you looking for?
米拉说那个太贵了...
Meera says it's too expensive...
你还记得我们在浦那的阿姨吗？
Do you remember our aunt in Pune?
她告诉我，去找找智者...
She told me to meet the Panditji...
智者...
Panditji...
我的意思是...操办宴会...
I mean... catering...
你得去看看操办宴会的人...
you need to meet the catering people...
他们通知我们很多次了
they've called so many times
哦，上帝，我完全忘了
Oh god I totally forgot
今天就去
Meet them today
我们一起去
Let's go together
等我快速地换一下衣服...
Let's get dressed quickly...
我们先去找茹阿达，然后再准备午餐
we'll meet Radha and do lunch after that
怎么了？
What's wrong?
突然头痛欲裂...
Suddenly got a splitting headache...
需要吃药吗？
Need some medicine?
不用了，我睡会儿就会好的
No...I should be fine if I sleep for a bit...
你赶快去吧
why don't you go ahead?
不过，Shashi...
But Shashi...
马努...那个更重要...
Manu...it's important...
以后你不会有时间了
you may not get the time later
“求求你...赶紧去吧...
Please...you must go...
那除非你答应好好睡觉
Only if you promise to sleep.
跟我念
Say it with me...
谁是明星？
who is the star?
我是明星...
I am the star...
不对...我是明星...
No...I'm the star...
对不起...
Sorry...
对不起，老师...迟到了...
sorry sir...late...
你在做什么好吃的吗？
What have you been cooking?
没有...迟到了...
No cooking...late...
进去吗？
Come in...?
你不可以
You may not...
再问一遍 Shashi
Ask again Shashi
进去吗？
Come in?
我没看见你...你在问我进没进来吗？
I can't see you... are you asking me to come in?
我能(can)进来
I can come in?
你能（can）进得来啊...门够宽了...
You can... the door is wide enough...
但是不允许(may not)你进来
but you may not!
为什么呢？
Why?
Shashi...你要问...“我可以进来吗？”
Shashi...you need to ask... 'may I come in?'
对不起...
Sorry...
我可以进来吗？
May I come in?
你可以！
You may!
我可以坐下吗？
May I sit down?
你可以
You may
“may”是什么  -“may”？
What is May - May?
我能把这个寄回印度吗？
May I send this back to India?
我能回家了吗？
May I go home now?
我能顺路载你一程吗？
May I give lift to you?
我能给你一巴掌吗？
May I give slap to you?
我能和你一起喝咖啡吗？
May I have a coffee with you?
今天不行...
Not today...
不行？好吧...
No? Ok...
那我能和一起同行吗？
May I have a walk with you?
你做的食物...
Your food...
我不行..
No...
你是酒店大厨...是专家...
you cooking hotel...expert...
我只是
I-m
在家里做做饭...
in house cooking...
都是些小菜
very small
才不是
No...
不是小菜
not small...
做饭是
food is...
一门艺术
food is art...
当男人做饭，就是艺术...
When a man cooks, it's art...
当女人做饭，这就是责任
when a woman cooks, it's her duty
你刚才说什么？
What did you just say?
对不起...
I'm sorry...
男人做饭...是艺术
Man cooking... art
女人做饭...
Lady cooking...
是日常生活中的责任！
daily job...duty!
不对
No...
做饭要有...
Food is...
爱
love
你用爱做饭，就会很好吃
You cooking with love, good food
你让大家都开心
You make people happy
你就是艺术家！
You artiste!
这不是小事
Not small...
你可以在这里开个餐厅...
You must open restaurant here...
在纽约！
in New York!
我不行...你能开
No...you open
也许吧...有一天...
Maybe...one day...
法国 印度餐厅！
French-Indian restaurant!
法国 印度餐厅
French...
你做的是...意大利面吗？
you make...pasta shaasta...?
不是
No...
意大利面是意大利美食
Pasta is Italian food
哦，法式和意式不是相同的吗？
Oh French, Italian not same?
完全不同！
No...no way!
例如...
For example...
看到那白色的东西了吗？
this white thing?
Iasoon（大蒜）
That's Iasoon...(Garlic)
意大利食品里大蒜无处不在
Italian food lasoon everywhere
法式菜肴就不是
French food...not everywhere
你在拉杜球里加大蒜吗？
You put lasoon in ladoos?
不！
No!
加糖...
Sugar...
甜蜜的...
sweet sweet...
甜品！
Dessert!
你能让我尝尝你的拉杜球吗？
You bring me sweet Iadoos?
OK！
OK!
你要买票吗？
You want ticket?
L-A-S-O-O-N
大...蒜
象拉杜球
L-A-D-0-O
白色的拉杜球
White ladoo
超大的白色拉杜球
Big white ladoo
你住在这儿吗？
You stay here?
不是
No...
附近？
Near?
这不是你要到的站？
This not your station?
不
No...
我往反方向
opposite side...
地铁...返回...另一边...
train... back...other side...
返回？
Back?
我走了...
I go...
再见
Bye
Shashi...
希望她没事了...
Hope she's ok...
你们回来了？
You're back?
你感觉怎么样？
How are you feeling?
好多了
Much better
对不起，我们回来晚了
Sorry we're late
来吧，我们吃点东西...
Come let's eat something...
印度餐馆吗...晚上好...
Indian kitchen...good evening...
他是意大利人还是法国人？
Was he Italian or French?
答应我，你不会告诉任何人
Promise me you won't tell anyone?
有什么样的甜点？
What can I order for dessert?
发生什么事了？
What happened?
妈妈...看到一只老鼠...
Mom...l saw a rat...
好大一只老鼠...
a really big rat...
往那边跑了
And it went that way!
我去拿棍子
I'll just get the stick
英语学习班？
English classes!
太棒了！
That's awesome!
非常非常高兴见到你！
Very very happy to meet you!
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you
Shashi 女士...
Shashi madam...
我们一起逃课去看电影吧
let us all bunk and go for movie
要说“A”电影...
'A' movie...
是啊，反正大卫老师今天也不来了
Yes David Sir is absent today
甚至那非洲人也病了
Even that Africa is sick madam...
逃课的家伙
bunking fellow
我们去看场好电影吧
Let us all go for a fine film
不是好电影，是看英语电影
No fine film...English film!
很显然，我们会看英语电影...我们又不是中国人
Obviously we'll watch an English film... not Chinese
我们都去看英语电影吧
We will all go watch English movie
你想加入我们吗？
You want to join us?
不...不...
No...no...
女士，你来了，请...我买爆米花
Madam you come please... I buy popcorn
我还有课
I have class
不幸的是，我的老师没有生病
Unfortunately my teacher hasn't fallen sick
我得走了
I gotta go
阿姨，你一定要去...
Aunty...you must go...
I'll see you after class...bye!
再见，茹阿达！
Bye Radha!
（经典爱情片《我最后一次看见巴黎》）他说什么？
What he say?
他说...你需要的是爱...
He say... all you need is love...
每个人都应该爱上...
everyone should love...
在你的右手边的人，并且亲吻他
and kiss people on your right hand side
萨尔曼...
Salman...
闭嘴！
shut up!
很精彩的电影，是吧？
Wonderful movie no madam?
精彩？你喜欢它吗？
Good? You like it?
那么深的爱...真美好
So much love...beautiful
Shashi...你喜欢这部电影吗？
Shashi... you like the movie?
很好的学习英语的机会...
Good English practice...
是啊...
Yeah...
是啊...很好的学习英语的机会...
Yeah... good English practice
- 抱歉稍等 - 没问题
- One second - No problem
喂？
Hello?
见鬼 我的剪贴簿去哪儿了？
Where the hell is my scrapbook?
我敢肯定是你把它收到什么地方了
I'm sure you've kept it somewhere...
快告诉我
tell me quick
Sapna...你嚷什么？
Sapna... why are you yelling?
到底在哪儿？
Where is it?
你为什么不冷静下来
Why don't you calm down
我如何冷静下来，妈妈？
How do I calm down mom?
为什么你要动我的东西？
Why do you touch my things?
我告诉过你多少次了，不要动我的东西！
How many times have I told you not to touch my things!
你看看你衣柜的第二个架子
Check the second shelf in your cupboard...
在你睡衣下面放着呢
...it's safely tucked away under your pyjamas
这样就没人会去看了
so that no one reads it...
我也没有看过
I didn't read it either
那是因为你看不懂
That's because you can't read...
一切OK了吗？
All ok?
有什么权力做孩子的...
What right do children have...
可以这样对待自己的父母？
...to treat their parents like this?
他们根本不懂得尊重！
They don't even know the meaning of respect!
我象一个垃圾...
Am I a trash can...
他们随意就可以丢弃
...to dump in whatever they feel like?
这是什么样的关系？
What kind of a relationship is this?
我们竭尽所能，让他们快乐...
We do our best to make them happy...
他们却轻易地用伤害来回报
and how easily they hurt you in return
孩子应该是天真无邪的...
Kids are supposed to be innocent...
可这是哪门子的天真无邪？
what kind of innocence is this...
利用我们的弱点...
taking advantage of our weakness...
什么都有可能教会别人
You can teach everything...
但你怎么教一个人
but how do you teach someone...
去在意别人的感受？
to be sensitive to others?
我要一杯拿铁咖啡...
I will have a cafe latte...
还要一个双层芝士蔬菜三明治和一杯冰水，谢谢
a double cheese vegetable sandwich and a glass of iced water please
先生，你呢？
And you sir?
卡布奇诺，谢谢...
Cappuccino please...
小杯
Small
Shashi...
你看到了吗？
YOU see?
什么？
What?
你点餐时...
You order...
太棒了
perfect
你点餐...完全正确的英语
You order...correct English
刚刚？
Now?
所有...冰水...
All...ice water...
是的，你做到了！
Yes...you did it!
我做到了！
I did it!
很好听，但我一句也不懂
Good to talk...without understanding!
慢慢地就会好的
Sometimes better
这是什么感觉
What a feeling!
无忧无虑的走着！
I walk carefree!
不要让我停止脚步
Don't ask me to stop
就让我大步前行
Just let me go on
我不害怕
I have no fear
我不担心
I have no worry
但愿不要失去自我
I hope I don't lose my way
如果真是那样...希望我能重新找到方向
If I do..-may the road find me!
不要让我停止脚步
Don't make me stop!
我已经改变了我的视角
I've changed my point of view
周围的一切是新的
Everything around is new
我很高兴开心，这是为什么？
I'm happy-vappy why oh why?
因为我很忙碌充实
I'm busy-vusy that is why!
非凡的！
Extraordinary!
如此激情！
This passion!
早上到中午！
Morning noon!
非凡的！
Extraordinary!
如此激情！
This passion!
早上到中午！
Morning noon!
一切尽在印式英语！
It's all about English Vinglish!
咖啡 Voffee 糖 Vugar
Coffee-Voffee Sugar-Vugar
纸 汽 相 新闻 Vews
Paper-Vaper News-Vews
马努，我在想...
Manu, I was thinking...
这个自助餐...
this buffet system...
一起站着吃
...standing and eating with plates in hand
会很不舒服
is so uncomfortable
如果我们采用印度的方式
If we're doing it all in Indian style...
让客人坐着，然后给他们上菜
then we should serve food while they're seated
好主意！
Excellent idea!
然后再做些 shagun ...
And something for shagun...
Shagun ...那是什么？
Shagun...what's that?
在婚礼上给客人的小礼物...
A small gift for the guests at the wedding...
礼物？我们不是应该收礼物吗？
Gift? Shouldn't we be receiving the gifts?
我的意思是“回礼”...
I mean 'return gift'...
用糖果的形式送给客人
in the form of sweets to be given to guests
那我需要叫外卖
I'll need to order that
不要外卖...我自己来做吧！
No order vorder...I'll make it myself!
真的吗？
Really?
说什么？
What was that?
凯文...我们只是在讨论
Kevin...we were just discussing
你需要给我买多少金银珠宝...
how much gold you need to buy us...
要很多很多公斤哦
lots and lots of kilograms of gold
你们听说了吗？
You hear?
大卫老师和男友分手了！
Sir David and boyfriend break up!
老师很伤心
Sir David very sad
我知道了。
I know.
同性恋分手有什么好伤心的？
Nothing sad about gay people breaking up...
丢了一个再找另一个就是！
drop one and pick another!
萨尔曼，不要这样说
Salman...don't say that
不要开玩笑
No making fun...
我们彼此不同
We are all different from each other
为你来说...大卫老师可能不“正常”...
For you... David Sir may not be 'normal'...
同样，对于大卫老师来说...你可能也不“正常”...
for David Sir... you may not be 'normal'...
但感情都是一样的...
but feelings are all the same...
痛苦就是痛苦...
and pain is pain...
她说什么？
What she say?
她说大卫老师与你们不同...
She say David sir different for you...
你们也不同于大卫老师
you different for David sir...
但心痛的感觉是一样的
but heart pain same same
对不起，女士...
Sorry madam...
那家伙是谁？
Who is this fellow?
谁伤了大卫老师的心？
Who break David Sir?
男朋友
Boyfriend
真让人心碎
Heart fracture
大家好...我回来了
Hello...I'm back
今天我们要谈...
Today we are going to talk...
沟通...
communicate...
表达...和分享...
express...share...
我们认为的...我们觉得...
what we think...what we feel...
对于生活
about life
对于这个城市...的思考和体会
about this city...
就在这节课上
this class!
拉玛...你有什么话要说？
Rama...you have something to say?
老师，我有很多话要说...
Sir...l have lot to say...
我有很多（A）话要说...
I have 'a' lot to say...
是的，老师...
Yes Sir...
我...
My...
我感触最深的...
My deepest feeling...
就是要让那些家伙明白
is to teach them such a lesson
这样的教训...
such a lesson...
谁，拉玛？
Who Rama?
哦，对不起...
Oh sorry...
我想给办公室的人上一课
I want to teach the office peoples big lesson
他们觉得...我是一个白痴...
They're thinking... no... he's a idiot...
只知道软件
only knowing the software
经常在我背后嘲笑
Making fun of my behind
...我的英语
...of my English
但是我就要让他们瞧瞧
But now I will show them
拉玛是拉玛先生！
that Ramamurthy is Mr. Ramamurthy!
我要让他们瞧瞧我的能耐！
I will show them what I can do!
美国很大...
America big place...
还很美丽
beautiful place
我现在就是想念两件事
I missing two things very terribly
我的年糕和我的母亲...
my idli (rice cake) and my mother...
我的母亲，然后才是年糕...
my mother then my idli...
请坐！
Please sit down!
英语班是一个大家庭
English class become one big family
没有国界...
No border problem...
萨尔曼兄弟，拉玛兄弟，我们是兄弟
Salman bhai, Rama bhai, we're brothers
阿姨...
Aunty...
伊娃，我的白姐姐
Eva my white sister
Shashi女士，我的印度姐姐...
Shashi madam, my Indian sister...
宋雨，我的黄色...
and Yu Son my yellow...
对不起
sorry
宋雨不是姐妹...
Yu Son not sister...
也不是黄色的...
Yu Son not yellow...
宋雨是粉红色的...
Yu Son pink...
宋雨美丽...
Yu Son beautiful...
宋雨是我的朋友，我最好的朋友
Yu Son my friend, my best friend
Udum... Udum bubke ...
Udum...Udumbubke...
我们可以听听你的感想吗？
can we hear your voice please?
我...？
Me...?
他会说话耶
He talks also?
我喜欢这个班
I like this class
我来到这个班是听英语的...
I come this class to listen English...
我平常不大说话
I don't talk much...
我就想听别人说话...
I want to listen people talk...
还有
and
我也是个...
I also...
...同性恋
...gay
又来一个！
Another one!
好样的！说得好极了！
Bravo! Very good!
好了...下一个是谁？
Ok...who is next?
洛朗，亲爱的，来这里，给我们讲讲
Laurent my love come up here and give us a speech
不，老师...
No sir...
我不喜欢汇报...
I don't like speech...
好吧好吧...
Fine fine...
那告诉我们你喜欢这个班的什么？
Tell us what you like about the class?
Shashi！
Shashi!
我同意...
I agree...
但你喜欢Shashi什么呢？
but what do you like about Shashi?
她很漂亮...
She is very beautiful...
她的眼睛像牛奶...
her eyes are like two drops of coffee...
上的两滴咖啡
on a cloud of milk
我来上课...
I come to class...
这样我就可以看到她了
so I can see her
Shashi...漂亮是吧？
So Shashi...beautiful eh?
洛朗...今天在课堂上你这样做，是不对的
Luaro...what you're doing in class today not correct...
洛朗，不是所有的女人都是法国人！
Laurent...all women not French!
印度的女人！你要尊重她们！
Indian woman! Show the respects!
我们不能接受在大庭广众之下调情
We don't ﬂirts in the open spaces in front of publics
我做什么？
What I do?
不是你做什么，是你做了什么！
Not what I do...what I did!
他还得上一个为期两年的英语课程...
He will need a two year course...
我很抱歉...
I am very sorry...
Shashi...
我真的很抱歉，你知道
I'm very sorry you know
我第一次看到你，在咖啡馆里，你还记得吗？
First time I see you in the café, you remember?
我认为漂亮就会说出口...
I think beautiful... I say beautiful...
过了这么多年还会
It's been ages since someone...
有人夸奖我
...said something nice about me
我只是吃了一惊....有点不习惯了
I was just taken aback... that's all
明天见
See you tomorrow
你这是怎么了？
What is the matter with you?
你为什么如此Judgemental...Judgemental（武断）...
Why are you being so judge... judgemental...
你是如此地Judgemental...
You're so judgemental...
Judgemental？
mental?
茹阿达
Rad ha...
对不起，茹阿达...
sorry Radha...
我有一个疑问...
I had a doubt...
我在看一部电影...
I was watching this film...
有个男子不断说那个女人Judgemental
this man keeps calling this woman 'judgemental'
我看她挺好的啊
She seemed fine to me...
他为什么要那样说她呢？
why was he calling her that?
什么是“Judgemental”，是什么意思？
What does 'judgemental' mean?
心理批判？
Mental judge?
阿姨！
Aunty!
你太搞笑了
You're too funny
Judgemental的意思...
Uudgemental' means..
你穿着传统服饰纱丽
You're wearing a traditional outfit...a sari
光看你的外表
Just by looking at you...
不去仔细想
without thinking...
不去了解你
without understanding...
不去认知你
without knowing you...
如果我就得出结论...
if I were to conclude...
你是一个典型的印度保守女人...
that you are a typical Indian conservative woman...
但实际上
when in reality
其实...你是一个有着自由思想的女性
actually... you're a free thinking woman
那么，我就叫...Judgemental
then I would be called... 'judgemental'!
Judgemental...
阿姨...
Aunty...
您想那么快了解这么多的英语啊？
you want to learn so much English so fast?
我时间不多啊，茹阿达
I have very little time Radha...
我可以再看些DVD吗？
Can I have more DVDs?
年糕和酸辣酱！
Idli (rice cakes) and chutney!
谢谢，女士
Thank you madam!
拉玛...控制一下自己
Rama... control your excitement
我还在这里呢
I am still here
但是年糕也在啊
ldli also here sir
哦，这就是年糕...看起来很美味
Oh that's idli...looks delicious
现在，我们还有一个星期的课程
Now...we have one week left to go
最后一天，你们有一个
And...on the last day you will have to take
考试！
an examination!
你们每人要准备5分钟的演讲
Each one of you will need to prepare a 5 minute speech
5分钟的演讲？
A full 5-minute speech?
用英语，拉玛...
English Rama please...
你们要先通过这项考试
You have to pass this exam before I can give you...
然后我才能给你们一个证书
a certificate that tells the world you are
证明你们有能力用英语交流了！
qualified to communicate in English!
不要这么难过
Don't look so sad
你们都将表现得很好的
You will all be wonderful
我敢肯定，你们都将出色地通过
I'm sure you will all pass with ﬂying colours
祝你们好运！
Good luck!
拉玛...
Rama bhai...
你不通过考试就没有证书
no certificate unless you pass the exam!
老师...什么时候考试？
Sir...when is exam?
28号...
The 28th...
28th...
28号！当天要举行婚礼啊
28th...that's the day of the wedding!
哪有时间准备演讲
Where is the time to prepare for speech...
没有“讲话”
no 'the' speech
怎么办...怎么办...
How to do...how to do...
打蜡和剪头发？
between waxing and hair cut?
你现在不得不学着多说点了，Udumbudum先生
You will have to talk very much now Mr. Udumbudum...
... Udumbke
...Udumbke
你还好吗？
You ok?
一切OK？
All ok?
28日考试...
28th exam...
当天的婚礼！
same day wedding!
不知道...
Don't know...
我没有...！
I didn't...!
没关系，我们坐上去再下来
It's ok...we go up and come down
等等...等等...
Wait...wait...
想不想看看
want to see something?
什么？
What?
来吧
Come
真美！
Beautiful!
太美了！
是啊
Yes
你还好吗？
You alright?
Shashi！
Shashi!
凌乱的心绪
Errant heart
Heart's in trouble
内心濒临陷落
There is trouble in the heart
凌乱的心绪
Errant heart
有点难以捉摸
A bit hard
有点怯懦胆小
A bit of a coward
你为什么停留在痛苦的门口？
Why do you stop at the doorway of pain?
为什么每次都只会折磨自己？
Why do you put yourself on trial each time?
为什么想哭的时候却假装欢笑？
Why do you laugh when you want to cry?
不能分清是非对错
You fail to decide between right and wrong
凌乱的心绪
Errant heart
内心濒临陷落
Heart's in trouble
凌乱的心绪
There is trouble in the heart
Errant heart
你的呼吸渐渐冰冷
Your breath is freezing cold
你的眼睛充满了迷雾
Your eyes are full of smoke
你在欢乐和痛苦之间下着赌注
Your constant gamble of joy and pain
你对希望有着永恒的信仰
Your eternal sense of hope
却无法面对自己
Your fear of yourself
为什么一个简单的旅程变得如此复杂
Why do you complicate an uncomplicated journey?
为什么不听听自己内心的真实想法
Why do you not listen to your own advice?
凌乱的心绪
Errant heart
妈妈！
Mama!
惊喜吧！
Surprise!
吓到了吧？
Shocked right?
你们不是下周才过来吗？
You were to come next week...
这是马努的想法，她想给你个惊喜
It was Manu's idea to surprise you
我们小心地策划...
We had to plan so carefully...
一直对你保密
to keep it a secret from you
甚至没有告诉茹阿达...那个大喇叭
Didn't even tell Radha... that broadcast channel
每个人都在等你...
Everyone's been waiting for you...
你去哪儿了
where did you disappear?
妈妈... 我吃了5包薯条...
Mama...l had 5 packets of chips...
喝了7瓶可乐...
7 cokes...
看了3部电影！
3 movies!
你怎么不说还有上了15次厕所！
And what about your 15 visits to the loo!
你要咖啡吗，Shashi？
Do you want coffee, Shashi?
凌乱的心绪
Errant heart
Heart's in trouble
内心濒临陷落
There is trouble in the heart
凌乱的心绪
Errant heart
有点难以捉摸
A bit hard
有点怯懦胆小
A bit of a coward
你到哪儿都是自己去的？
You go everywhere on your own?
不错啊
Not bad
即便是那些懂英语的人...
Even those who know English...
来纽约也会觉得困难...
find it difficult here in New York...
但你都搞定了...太厉害！
but you are managing on your own... amazing!
在家你不也是一个人搞定的吗?
You managed there on your own too... didn't you?
几乎是一个人...
Barely...
妈妈...我睡不着...
Mama...l can't sleep...
怎么办？
what do I do?
来妈妈这儿
Come to mama
现在你来照顾他吧...我该度假了
You take care of him now... I'm on holiday
睡吧，亲爱的...
Sleep my darling...
我的宝贝...
my baby...
我的小拉杜球
my ladoo...
Shashi 茶！
Shashi...tea!
摆个pose吧
Please pose
好了
Ok good
看看...
See...
看那边...
see over there...
Jhaaz！ Jhaaz！ Jhaaaz！
Jhaaz! Jhaaz! Jhaaaz!
不是爵士... 是jhaaz！
Not jazz... jhaaz!
接下来我们去帝国州（纽约州的别称）
And next we go to the Empire state
帝国州！我想看！
Empire State! I want to see it!
我想去看帝国！
I want to see Empire!
我们都去看帝国
We'll all see Empire
你们去吧
You people go ahead...
我留在这儿...
I'll stay here...
妈妈的腿真的走痛了
mama's legs are really aching
不行，妈妈...你也要一起来
No mama...you have to come
这里非常拥挤
It will be very crowded there
如果你腿痛...
And if your legs hurt...
确实不好...
not a good idea...
那里还远着呢
there will be really long lines
那我们先去了
We will go ahead...
你就放松下
you just chill
不！
No!
Sagar 你知道吗...
Sagar you know what...
那里有非常不错的冰淇淋店
there is this awesome ice cream place
叫做酷圣石冰淇淋店
It's called Cold Stone
你知道他们怎么做...
Do you know what they do...
他们拿石头打击冰淇淋...
they take a stone and beat up the ice cream...
然后加上糖浆和巧克力条
then they add gummy bears and
继续拍打
chocolate chips and beat it up again
走吧，让我们去打冰淇淋！
Come let's go beat up the ice cream!
走吧，走吧
Come let's go!
萨蒂什叔叔，走吧
Satish uncle let's go...
Shashi...等等
Shashi...wait
我做了法式甜点...
I cook french dessert...
可丽饼...
crepe...
你试试，然后告诉我...
you try, you tell me...
你为什么老是纠缠我呢？
Why don't you leave me alone!
你知不知道...
Don't you know...
我是一个已婚的女人
I'm a married woman
你知不知道...
Don't you know...
我是两个孩子的母亲
I'm a mother of two children
你知不知道...
Do you know...
他们都在帝国大厦等我
they are all waiting for me at the Empire State Building
所以请告诉我...
So tell me...
我是与你坐在人行道上
should I sit here with you on the sidewalk
一起吃你的法式薯条
and eat french fries
还是应该去找我的家人呢？
or should I go to my family?
Shashi...
什么？
What?
帝国大厦...应该往这边
The Empire state building... is this way
法式薯条不是法式菜肴...
French fries is not french...
这是一个美国人的想法
it's an American concept
这是法式拉杜球
This is french ladoo...
70％的巧克力
with organic chocolate 70 %
如果你喜欢，还可以加热吃
you can make it warm if you want
妈妈！
Mama!
Sagar！
Sagar...!
发生什么事了？
What happened?!
他突然出现在皮球的线路上
He got in the way of the ball...
我去拿些水...
I'll go get some water...
妈妈！- 怎么了？
Mama...! - How did it happen?
妈妈去哪儿了？
Where's mom?
你还伤到别的地方了没有？
Are you hurt anywhere else?
你能打电话给Shashi吗，茹阿达？
Can you please call Shashi Radha?
妈妈的电话在我这儿！
Mom's phone is with me!
Shashi在哪里？
Where is Shashi?
她去哪里了？
Where did she disappear?
OK，我们走吧...
Ok come let's go...
让我们首先照顾Sagar
let's take care of Sagar first...
然后我会回来找阿姨
and I will come back for aunty
勇敢点，你会没事的！
Brave boy...you'll be ok!
妈妈...你知道发生了什么吗？
Mama...do you know what happened?
好大一个球飞来...
Big ball came...
我就跌倒了
and I fell
我没有看见球飞过来...
I didn't see the ball coming...
否则...我会踢它的
otherwise...one kick!
骗子...
Liar...
没什么大不了的...只是一点点擦伤...
Nothing happened... just a little scratch...
你看看他...大惊小怪！
and look at him now...fuss pot!
Sagar 是一个坚强的男孩
Sagar is a strong boy
吃块饼干
have a cookie...
喝点牛奶
drink your milk...
一个有魔力的妈妈的吻，一切都会好起来
One magic kiss from mama and all will be well
你的腿痛怎么样了？
How's the pain in your leg?
肯定很痛了...所以才不和我们一起
You must have been in a lot of pain... to not come with us...
自己离开了
but take off by yourself
如果你不再喜欢和我们在一起...
If you don't like being with us any more...
你应该告诉我们...
you should have told us...
我们也就不会到这里来
we wouldn't have come here
萨蒂什...你在说什么...
Satish...what are you saying...
你说我说什么呢？
What do you mean...'what'?
Shashi 你怎么了？
What's happened to you Shashi?
看起来你一个人反而更高兴
It looks like you were happier alone
我只是...
I was just...
感谢上帝，我没有让孩子与你一起先来
Thank god I didn't send the kids earlier with you
就这样吧
That's it!
我受够了这个英语！
Enough of this English!
我是怎么了？
What's happened to me?
英语比我的孩子还重要吗？
English has become more important than my children!
阿姨  什么事也没有...Sagar 好好的
Aunty nothing happened... Sagar is fine
不，茹阿达
No Rad ha
我应该与大家一起去的
I should have come along with you all
我已经变得如此自私...
I have become so selfish...
忘记了我的责任
I have forgotten my responsibilities
我不该来这里去学习什么英语
I didn't come here to learn English
够了！这个印式英语该结束了！
Enough! I'm done with this English Vinglish!
阿姨 不要放弃
Aunty don't do that... don't give up now
就只剩下3、4节课了
Just 3-4 classes left to go...
在3、4天里，我还能学到什么？
What more will I learn in 3-4 days?
请告知他们
Please inform them
我不学了
I'm quitting
阿姨...求你...
Aunty...please...
你应该有始有终
just finish what you started"!
既然自己开的头，就要自己完成，不是吗？
You should finish what you started right?
我更要完成...
I want to finish...
多年以前开的头
what I started long ago...
做回我孩子的母亲
being a mother to my children
我要找大卫老师
I am looking for Professor David
他就在这里！
Right here!
你好，我是大卫...
Hi, I'm David...
嗨...我是茹阿达，Shashi的外甥女
Hi... I'm Radha, Shashi's niece
这就是Shashi的外甥女...
This is Shashi's niece...
见到你很高兴
so good to meet you
我有一些坏消息要告诉你
I have some bad news for you
Shashi 不会再来上课了
Shashi's not gonna be able to make it to class any more
不...她还没考试呢！
No...she has to take her exam!
我知道...但她的家人已经从印度过来的...
I know...her family has come down from India...
而且我们忙于我姐姐的婚礼...
and we're busy with my sister's wedding...
我给你我的名片...
I'll give you my card...
你让她给我打个电话
you have her call me
你好！
Bonjour!
你怎么样？
How are you?
茹阿达...？
Rad ha...?
Shashi 在吗？
Shashi here?
不，她不在
No she isn't here...
我来是告诉大卫老师
I came to talk to David about it...
她不会再来上课了
she's not going to take class any more...
为什么呢？考试对她很重要啊
Why? Exam very important for Shashi
我知道...但是我姐姐要结婚，...
I know...my sister is getting married and...
她的家人也从印度过来了，所以很遗憾
her family has come down from India, so unfortunately...
能告诉我电话号码吗？
Can I ask for telephone number?
拉杜球来啦！
Ladoo sampling!
- 凯文...尝一个  - 谢谢
- Kevin...try one... - Thank you...
这个太好吃了
This is incredible...
我愿意为这个一而再，再而三地结婚
I could get married again and again for this
只和你...一次又一次
To you...to you...again and again
哇！Shashi 阿姨 太好吃了！
Wow...! Shashi Aunty it's amazing!
你知道吗，凯文...这是你这辈子能吃到的最好的拉杜球了
You know Kevin...these are the best ladoos you will ever eat
我完全同意
I totally agree
我的妻子，她生来就是做拉杜球的
And my wife, she was born to make Iadoos...
我这是在表扬你
I just gave you a compliment...
你生来就是做拉杜球的
you were born to make Iadoos!
马努...我们可以把金盏花放在这儿...
Manu... we can put marigolds here...
茉莉花放在那边
and jasmine there...
还有其他插花...
and the other flower arrangements...
妈妈...何塞打电话给你...
Mama...José is calling you...
阿姨...你生来不光是做拉杜球的
Aunty...you were not born only to make ladoos
Sagar 来这里...
Sagar come here...
萨尔曼，你来说说你最喜欢的电影
Salman why don't you tell me the story of your favourite film
我最喜欢的电影是...
My favourite movie is...
欲望都市
Sex and City
这是4个性感女孩的故事...
It is story of 4 sexy girls...
走在城市中，谈论性的故事
talking of sex and walking on the city
非常好看
Very pretty
老师，我非常非常喜欢 Rajnikanth 的电影
Sir...l like the Rajnikanth film very very much
Rajnikanth 不是演员
Rajnikanth is not a actor...
他是一个神！
he's a god!
他可以去掉超人的内裤...
He can remove the underwear of the superman...
他可以用鼻子接子弹...
he can catch a bullet with his nose...
外婆...我要跳“dhinka”这首歌
Granny... I will dance to the 'dhinka chika' song
Sagar...你跳这支歌...
Sagar... dance to this song instead...
这歌太无聊了！
What a boring song!
Sagar，这首歌很棒！
Sagar it's awesome!
Sapna，跟我来！
Sapna, come with me!
我亲爱的养尊处优最喜欢的新娘
My sweet pampered favourite bride
她爱和希望的月亮
She loves and desires the moon
我这甜美娇羞的新娘子
My sweet pampered favourite bride
她热爱并渴望着月亮
She loves and desires the moon
我这上帝祝福的孩子
My God given blessed child
就是上帝身边的美丽天使
Angelic beauty of the Gods
我希望明天看到我最喜欢的学生...
I hope to see my favourite student tomorrow...
我会尽力的...大卫老师...
Trying...David sir...
不需要拼命的，Shashi
No trying vying Shashi
考试又不是什么生命和死亡的问题...
Taking an exam is not a matter of life and death...
只是为了向自己证明，我能做到而已
it's about the joy of telling yourself that you have done it
Shashi 女士...
Shashi madam...
最后一堂课...
last day of class...
我们真的很想念你
we really miss you
演讲准备好了吗，女士？
Speech ready no madam?
明天会来吗，夫人？
Coming tomorrow no madam?
婚礼在明天...下午...
The wedding is tomorrow... afternoon...
没问题，夫人！
No problem madam!
明天上午考试...就1个小时
Tomorrow exam morning... 1 hour exam...
你可以轻轻地来，然后又轻轻地走！
like that only you come... like that only you go!
Shashi，来吧
Shashi please come
我明天肯定不合格，但我也会来
I am failing tomorrow and I am here
Shashi 你一定要来...
Shashi you must come...
也许一起喝杯咖啡？
One cup of coffee maybe?
阿姨...他真的喜欢你！
Aunty...he really likes you!
你是不是也...
Do you also...?
没关系啊...很正常...
It's ok... it happens...
茹阿达...
Rad ha...
我不需要爱情...
I don't need love...
我真正需要的是...
what I really need is...
是尊重！
some respect!
请问你能帮我...
Will you help me...
最后一次吗？
one last time?
我想明天参加考试
I want to take the exam tomorrow
哦，听...要好好照顾她
O listen...take care of her
她是一朵娇嫩的花
She is delicate blossom
她是珍贵的
She is precious
她独一无二
She is a rare one
跳起舞来吧
Come all dance along
让我们沉浸在欢乐中
Let's drown in joy
跟着这首快乐的歌
To this happy song
她的眼睛...会说话
Her eyes... they speak
会挑逗...还会偷偷地
They tease... they sneak
进入梦的世界
into the world of dreams
一切都是明亮的金黄和碧绿！
All bright and gold and green!
害羞的新娘来了
Here goes the shy blushing bride
她婀娜地走向爱人
She sways to her beloved's charms
在她深色的眼睛里闪烁着魔力
Magic in her dark kohl eyes
我来到美国...
I come to America...
我想学习英语...
I want to learn English...
为了获得更好的工作...
To get a better job...
我想学好英语...
I want to learn better English...
成为更有用的人...
to become the better person...
然后我就可以去上大学...
I can then go to college...
我不知道我为什么要学英语...
I didn't know why I wanted to learn English...
巴基斯坦女孩 中国女孩...
Pakistani girl Chinese girl...
今天不载客...明天再来
No... come tomorrow
我可以教美国人西班牙语！
I teach all America Spanish!
Shashi 在哪里？
Where's Shashi?
拉杜球得赶紧拿出来了
The ladoos have to be taken out...
还需要做成礼品包装
...need to be gift wrapped
妈妈...大家肯定会喜欢拉杜球做礼物的
Chill mom...people are going to love the ladoo gift pack
Shashi 阿姨很能干
Shashi aunty is amazing
- 我希望妈妈你也有这种天赋   - 好啊！
- I wish mom had some of that talent - Yeah right!
你喜欢哪种...
Who do you fancy...
美国男孩还是印度男孩？
American guys or Indian?
哎哟，你妈妈来了！
Crap it's your mum...!
怕什么...她又听不懂
Chill...she won't understand
那么，你男朋友的名字叫什么？
So what's your boyfriend's name?
我还没有呢...你呢？
I don't have one...do you?
我也没有
No...
阿姨，已经8点半了
Aunty its already 8.30
不要忘了...我们还要去美容院
Don't forget... we need to go to the beauty salon
让我来帮你
Let me help you with that
把另外一个盘子拿过来
Bring the other tray
马努阿姨，快来！
Manu aunty...come quickly!
Sagar在哪里？
Where is Sagar?
阿姨，我们在回来的路上再买吧...
Aunty...we can buy them on the way back...
Shashi...
Yes Shashi...
附近就有一个印度甜品店...
there's an Indian sweet shop near by...
不用担心...
don't worry...
但是现在，没有人能品尝到阿姨的拉杜球了！
Now no one will get to taste Aunty's ladoos!
到这里来
Come here.
我告诉过你多少次了要守规矩
How many times have I told you to behave?
难道我没告诉你吗？
Didn't I warn you?
你还敢不敢这样做？
Will you do it again?
还敢不敢？
Will you?
够了
Stop it
我重做 ...
I will make fresh ladoos again...
全部？
All over again?
那太费心了，Shashi！
All that trouble again Shashi!
是啊...
Yes...
但我会做
I will
对不起，请帮我...
Excuse me... please help me with that...
萨蒂什...我来弄就行
Satish...I'll get it done
好吧，现在该怎么办？
It's ok...what to do!
阿姨...
Aunty...
我们要走了...
we need to leave...
如果我在我最喜欢的事情上都做不好...
What's the point if I fail in my favourite subject...
做好其它的又有什么意义？
and pass in the other?
萨提什，照顾一下他们...
Satish look after them...
我听到很多关于你妻子的拉杜球的手艺
I've heard so much about your wife's food...Iadoos?
她喜欢做饭...
She loves cooking...
我喜欢吃！
And I love eating!
谢谢你们的光临
Thank you for coming
恭喜！
Congratulations!
祝喜 米拉！
Hi Radha!
嗨 - 我买了花
Hi - I bought ﬂower
谢谢
Thank you
宋雨！
Yu Son!
你好！
Hello!
你看起来很...漂亮！
You are looking very...correct!
非常感谢你打电话邀请我们
Thank you very very much for calling us to come
真不明白他是怎么通过英语考试的
Can't understand how he got through the English exam
Shashi 在哪里？
Where is Shashi?
Shashi 阿姨正在准备...
Shashi aunty is getting ready...
我可以去帮忙吗？
May I go helping?
不用，她很快就会忙完的...谢谢
No, she'll be here soon... thank you
天知道她怎么也通过了考试
God knows how she also got through the exam
你说什么？
What you say?
我说我爱你
I say I love you
Shashi！哦，你看起来真漂亮！
Shashi! Oh you look so beautiful!
Shashi 女士，我们今天真想你啊
Shashi madam...we missed you today
我的演讲很有水平
What a speech I gave...
相当有水平！
What a speech!
我一个字也没听懂
I not understand one word
拉玛兄弟也一样，很棒的英语！
Rama bhai also...superb english!
不要叫我拉玛兄弟...
Don't call me Rama bai...
这是我在印度的仆人的名字！
that is my servant's name in India!
哦，Shashi，你这么漂亮...
Oh Shashi you look so beautiful...
谢谢你...你也是
Thank you...you too!
大卫老师！
David sir!
感谢上帝，茹阿达邀请我们所有人参加婚礼
Thank god Radha invited all of us to the wedding
我可不能让你不再见一面就离开
I couldn't let you leave without meeting me
谢谢你们的到来
Thank you so much for coming
Shashi...你在做什么？
Shashi...what are you doing?
婚礼即将开始...
The wedding is about to begin...
萨蒂什叔叔...
Satish uncle...
萨蒂什...这是大卫老师...
Satish...this is David Sir...
Udumbke ...
Udumbke...
EVA ...
Eva...
萨尔曼...宋雨...
Salman...Yu Son...
Ramamurthy ...- 很高兴见到你。
Ramamurthy... - Nice to meet you.
洛朗...
Laurent...
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you
他们是我的好朋友
They are my close friends
Shashi，仪式要开始了
Shashi, it's time for the ceremony
敬我亲爱的女儿米拉，我亲爱的儿子凯文...
To my darling daughter Meera and my dear son Kevin...
我多么希望阿尼尔也在这里
How I wish Anil was here
当我的米拉进入青春期的时候
When Meera was going through her troubled teens...
她才14岁 ...
she was 14...
她当时只有14岁...
she was only 14 years old...
她怒气冲冲地跑来问我们
when she came in fuming and asked us...
你们为什么要生下我？
Why did you give birth to me?'
她很愤恨生活...
She was so angry with life...
她大发雷霆，说我们生下了她
that she was furious that we gave birth to her
却没有经过她的许可！
without asking for her permission!
今天我会回答你 米拉
I will answer that today Meera
你的出生...
You were born...
让你的爸爸和我可以享受到无尽的快乐
so your dad and I could share complete happiness
你的出生给我们的生活带来幸福
"You were born so you could bring happiness into our lives..."
我很抱歉没有经过你的许可
I am so sorry I didn't take your permission
我爱你们俩个
Love you both sweethearts!
愿上帝永远保佑你们
God bless both of you always
儿子...你很幸运！
Son... you just got lucky!
但幸运之神只会降临到懂得珍惜的人身上
But fortune smiles on those who embrace it's offerings...
所以...要彼此相爱
so... love each other
还有，儿子...
And son...
我和你的母亲要独自离开了
leave me and your mother alone!
该是时候多多关爱彼此了
It's time for us to focus on each other
Shashi阿姨...轮到你了
Shashi Aunty...your turn
是啊...说吧
Yes... come on
阿姨
Aunty
对不起...我妻子的英语...
Sorry... my wife's English is...
不是很好，所以...
not very good so...
我可以吗？
May I?
米拉...
Meera...
凯文...
Kevin...
这场婚礼是...
this marriage is a...
哎呀，对不起...我说了印地语
Oops sorry... I started in Hindi
这场婚礼...真的是
This marriage is a
一件美丽的事
beautiful thing
这也是一种友谊
It is the most
一种特殊友谊的...
special friendship...
完美升华
friendship of two people
两个平等的人之间的友谊
who are equal
人生是一个漫长的旅程
Life is a long journey
米拉，有时你会觉得
Meera, sometimes you will feel
自己比较弱势一些
you are less
凯文，有时你也会
Kevin, sometimes you will also
觉得你比米拉弱势一些
feel you are less than Meera
尝试互相帮助
Try to help each other
彼此平等相待
to feel equal
这样才好
It will be nice
有时候...
Sometimes...
夫妻之间甚至不知道
married couple don't even know
对方的感觉
how the other is feeling
那么...他们将如何能相互扶持？
So... how they will help the other?
婚姻这时岂不是就意味着结束？
It means marriage is finished?
其实也不会
No
这种时候
That is the time
你必须帮助自己
you have to help yourself
因为没有人比你自己更能帮助你了
Nobody can help you better than you
如果你这样做了...
If you do that...
你才可能会重新感觉到平等
you will return back feeling equal
你们之间的友谊又会重新被找回
your friendship will return back...
你们的生活将依旧美好
your life will be beautiful
米拉...凯文...
Meera...Kevin...
也许你们今后将会非常忙...
maybe you'll very busy...
但是家庭...
but have family...
儿子...女儿...
son...daughter...
无论是在这个大的世界里...
in this big world...
还是你们的小世界里
your small little world
都会让你们感觉到幸福
It will make you feel so good
家人...
Family...
家人永远不会...
family can never be...
永远不会武断地评价你！
never be judgemental!
家人永远不会...
Family will never...
贬低你...
put you down...
不会让你感到自己的渺小
will never make you feel small
家人是唯一不会
Family is the only one
嘲笑你的弱点的人
who will never laugh at your weaknesses
家庭是唯一一个
Family is the only place
总能找到
where you will always get
爱和尊重的地方
love and respect
我就说这么多了，米拉和凯文...
That's all Meera and Kevin...
我祝你们幸福美满
I wish you all the best
谢谢
Thank you
哦，Shashi...
Well Shashi...
你用了“返回”，你应该用“return”...
you don't 'return back', you just return...
你还掉了了几个“a”和“the”
and you missed a few 'a's and 'the's...
还有，你以优异的成绩毕业啦！
else you passed with distinction!
Shashi阿姨，你真棒！
Shashi aunty you were amazing!
是的...我真为你感到骄傲
Yes... I'm so proud of you
要我帮忙吗？
Do you want me to help?
那帮我拿其它的盘子吧
Bring the other tray
下次你在妈妈面前说英语时
Next time you speak in English in front of mama...
最好想想...她比你说得更好！
please think... she can talk better than you!
大卫老师...尝尝拉杜球！
David Sir... ladoo!
谢谢...我还有一些东西给你！
Thank you... I have some thing for you!
当你不喜欢自己...
When you don't like yourself...
你就会不喜欢自己周围的一切
you tend to dislike everything connected to you
新的东西似乎更有吸引力
New things seem to be more attractive
但当你学会爱自己...
When you learn to love yourself...
原来沉寂的旧生活...
then the same old life...
就会开始变得焕然一新
starts looking new...
变得更加美好
starts looking nice
谢谢你...
Thank you...
教会了我...
for teaching me...
如何爱自己！
how to love myself!
谢谢你让我开始...
Thank you for making me...
对自己有了信心
feel good about myself
太感谢你了！
Thank you so much!
吃拉杜球吧...
Ladoo...
你伤了法国人的心，不是吗？
Broke the French heart, didn't you?
Shashi...
你...
Do you...
还爱我吗？
still love me?
如果我不爱...
If I didn't...
为什么我要多给你一个拉杜球呢？
why would I give you two ladoos?
还有...
And...
眼光不错！
good choice!
她的眼睛...会说话
Her eyes... they speak
会挑逗...还会偷偷地
They tease... they sneak
进入梦的世界
into the world of dreams
所有的一切都是明亮的金黄和碧绿！
All bright and gold and green!
害羞的新娘来了
Here goes the shy blushing bride
她婀娜地走向爱人
She sways to her beloved's charms
她深色的眼睛闪烁着魔力
Magic in her dark kohl eyes
你喜欢看什么报纸，先生？
What newspaper would you like sir?
“纽约时报”，谢谢
New York Times please
你呢，太太？
And you ma'am?
纽约...
The New York...
对不起...你们有印地语报纸吗？
sorry...do you have any Hindi newspaper?
没有，对不起
No, sorry
没关系...谢谢
It's ok...thank you.